SEJAL BADGUJAR

sejalnbadgujar@gmail.com|+91 9420841124

Professional Summary

About 4 years of industry experienced in .Net and Python programming and 3 years in teaching. Dual postgraduate MTech in embedded systems and PGDM in healthcare management with much project experience. Published papers in international journal and conference. Immensely interested in academics.

Education

Education	University/College	Specialization	Percentage/ CGPA	Year of Passing
Master in Technology (M.Tech)	Amrita Vishwa Vidyapitham, Coimbatore	Embedded Systems	8.82	2020
Post - Graduate Diploma in Management (Distance PGDM)	Welingkar Institute of Management Development & Research, Mumbai	Healthcare Management	64 %	2020
Bachelor of Engineering (BE)	Cummins College of Engineering for Women, University of Pune	Electronics and Telecommunication	71.33 % (GATE 2014,2016 Qualified)	2014
Higher Secondary Certificate (HSC)	K.R.Kotkar Junior College, Chalisgaon	-	90 %	2010
Secondary School Certificate (SSC)	A.B. Girls School, Chalisgaon	-	91.69 %	2008

Experience

1. K. K. Wagh Institute of Engineering and Research, Nasik

Assistant Professor

1st April, 2022 – Present

• Teaching as an assistant Professor (C, JAVA and advance JAVA, JavaScript)

2. WhiteHatJr. Coding Platform

Coding Teacher, Professional Curriculum

25nd Sept, 2020 – 1 December, 2022

- Teaching coding to the students at professional level using JavaScript and Python.
- Completed the courses offered.

3. Glisten Software Private Limited, Pune

Intern, Feb 2020 – July 2020

- Developed travel guide using Wikipedia text fetching and processing is done.
- Developed different modules of text analysis like word embedding with Word2vec and doc2vec, tagging, classification, calculation of cosine similarity using python.

4. AK Capitals, Nariman Point, Mumbai

Senior Developer, June 2017 - Jan 2018

• Developed an email notification system through SQL which shoots the mail to specific people for specific purposes.

- Team developed an application in banking field which is helping company people to reduce the paper work and access the data quickly and easily.
- The project was developed by using C#, angular JavaScript and SQL 2016.

5. Capgemini, Airoli

Senior Software Engineer, July 2014 - July 2016

- Enhanced and supported of applications of UK based insurance broker company Willis.
- Awarded with certificate of appreciation for my initiative in taking ability which helped immensely in the support of critical applications of Willis in Oct, 2015
- Automated the critical process of an application in SQL to reduce manual work and time requirement.
- Part of knowledge transfer for multiple applications and documented and presented the details of the applications to client.
- Supported one of the most important applications of Willis- 'Willplace' and its 49 interfaces as SSIS packages. Enhanced some packages in SSIS with various data sources.
- Managed team and trained the new members of the team.

6. Reliance Communications Limited, Pune

Intern, Nov -Dec, 2012

- Learnt about Networking in Reliance, working of Base Switching Center (BSC), basic structure of GSM and CDMA Technologies provided by Reliance in India.
- Worked on the projects of 'Site Planning' for mobile communication.

Publications

Paper Title	Conference/ Journal	Year
Algorithm for Insertion of DFT at specific nodes with least area overhead and time latency	International Journal of Computer Technology and Applications (IJCTA)	Sept,2014 Volume 5, Issue 5
Fall detection for elderly people using machine learning	International Conference On Computing, Communication And Networking Technologies (ICCCNT)	July,2020
Wearable sensor and machine learning model based fall detection system for safety of elders and movement disorders	Academia-Industry Consortium for Data Science (AICDS)	Jan, 2021

Coding Skills

Programming	Python , Embedded C, .Net C#, C, VHDL, HTML, JavaScript	
Database	MS SQL	
IDE used	MATLAB, Xilinx, MPLab, Keil, Multisim, Visual Studio, Kofax	

1)	Electronic Medical record system using Windows form C# for Ophthalmology doctors with facility of mailing the summary.	May-June, 2020
2)	Travel guide development using wikipedia data using Python. Topic modeling and word embedding using Word2Vec model.	Feb-May, 2020
3)	Fall detection system for elderly people using machine learning algorithms with high accuracy using Raspberry Pi, Python packages.	June, 2019-Feb, 2020
4)	Intelligent walking stick with obstacle detection and indoor localization using IoT By using triangulation techniques in python, Raspbery pi and TCP communication.	Dec-Apr, 2019
5)	Developed an algorithm for insertion of DFT at specific nodes with least area overhead and time latency. Published paper on the same.	Aug, 2013-Mar,201 4

Extra-Curricular Activities

- 1) Organizer of College Band.
- 2) Performed in two stage shows of Marathi play 'Firodiya Karandak 2012- Perte Vha'and 'Firodiya Karandak 2013-Tastuli'.
- 3) Member of Student Cultural co-panel 2013 of college.
- 4) Volunteered for Tech for Seva (TFS), social event.
- 5) Volunteered for ICARE (Social Event of IGATE).
- 6) Performed on IGATE cultural stage shows TGIM(Thank God Its Monday)

Personal Information

- Languages known: English, Hindi, Marathi
- Date of Birth: 20th March, 1993
- Marital status: Married
- Address: Blaize apartments, Asha pura housing society, Dhatrak phata, Nasik. (422003)
- Hobbies: Singing (Visharad), reading